

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Comfortable management of operating systems and terminals Windows, Linux and MacOS
- Git and Github
- Main programming lang: JavaScript / Node
- Layout and design with HTML and CSS languages
- SQL Databases
- Photoshop and Figma
- Currently learning React

SOFT SKILLS

I'm an enthusiastic, committed and responsible person, having worked for different business lines taught me a lot about teamwork and how to adopt to changes quickly, I enjoy learning and working in team environments as well as using my own initiative as a self-taught developer.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Phone: (999)2307660 E-mail: rivas060@gmail.com Address: Merida, Yucatan, Mexico

WEB PAGE AND GITHUB

https://xanul.github.io/myPortfolio/

https://github.com/Xanul

RODRIGO RIVAS MARTINEZ

PROFILE

I have always considered myself a technology and innovation lover, I started formally learning software development 2+ years ago, and since then it became a passion for me, I enjoy learning new tools and technologies every day and work on projects in the journey to become a professional full stack developer

WORK EXPERIENCE

MANAGER

Grupo Converse de México | Playa del Carmen, QRoo | Jun 2008 - Feb 2011

- Management and staff training
- Responsible for the optimal operation of the store
- Customer support and attention in English and Spanish
- Preparation of orders, sales and inventory reports
- Daily cash cuts and petty cash management

ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER

CER Seguros | Mérida, Yucatán | Mar 2013 - Nov 2016

- Client portfolio management
- Issuance and management of policies of various branches
- Direct claims assistance
- Monthly billing and finance managment

TELEMARKETING

Teleindigo | Mérida, Yucatán | Mar 2017 - Feb 2018

- Sales and customer service to United States customers
- Attendance at various language and customer management courses
- All the development of the work was in English

EDUCATION

LIC. DE INGENIERÍA EN AUDIO Y PRODUCCIÓN MUSICAL Academia de Música Fermata - | 2010 - 2012 (Truncated career)

LIC. DE INGENIERÍA EN DESARROLLO DE SOFTWARE Universidad abierta y a distancia de México (UnADM) - | 2020 -Presente

VARIOUS SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT COURSES MAINLY ON THE UDEMY, PLATZI AND FREECODECAMP PLATFORMS

LANGUAGES

- Native Spanish
- Advance English (C1) British Council